SELEPE THINANE

Fullstack Developer

+27 63 112 0386 • tumelothinane13@gmail.com • https://tumelothinane.netlify.app/ • linkedin.com/in/selepe-thinane • Gautenq, SA • github.com/Tumelo2748

Who am I

Full Stack Developer with 2 years of work experience and 1 bootcamp, Skilled in React, JavaScript, Supabase, RESTful services. I also have solid experience with backend technologies like Node.js, Express, and MongoDB building Restful APIs. Founder of ReapplyMe, an application aimed at automating job applications with ease of machine learning

Work Experience

Sandton, RSA Project-Y 2024 - Present

Full Stack Developer and Founding Member

Project Y is a digital nation that helps tech-minded individuals build essential skills for a successful career in technology. It offers top-tier education, career support, and community access, all designed to unlock opportunities in tech

- · Honed skills in key front-end technologies including React, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, alongside back-end expertise in Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, and Docker.
- Enhanced proficiency in Docker for streamlined containerization and mastered SQL for data manipulation.
- Demonstrated superior interpersonal abilities, excelling in team collaboration, strategic problem-solving, and clear communication.
- · Coordinated and contributed to the successful execution of 40 projects with project-y members, enhancing team collaboration and project outcomes.

Heilbron, RSA Euphorea Full Stack Developer 2022 - 2023

Euphorea is an entertainment brand specializing in music

- Optimized application performance by 40% by refactoring legacy code and implementing efficient algorithms.
- Increased user retention by 20% by implementing intuitive and responsive design in React-based web applications.
- Improved application load time, resulting in enhanced user experience and customer satisfaction.
- Enhanced user retention rates by 15% through improved UI/UX design.

Skills

Frontend; React · Nextjs · JavaScript · React Native · HTML · CSS · Redux · JavaScript · Tailwind css · Bootstrap · Typescript

Backend: NodeJS · Express · Swagger · FastAPI · PHP

DevOps: CI/CD · Docker · Kubernetes · AWS · Google cloud

Machine Learning: Python · TensorFlow · Cloud Computing · PyTorch · Transformers

Testing: Mocha · Jest

Database: SQL · MySQL · MongoDB · Firebase

Education

Remote Re:Coded

Full Stack Software Development and Artificial Intelligence 04/2024 - 10/2024

University of Johannesburg

Johannesburg, RSA 2020 - 2023 Business information Technology

Strengths



I am able to collaborate with different people on projects

Full stack expertise

Proficient in front-end and backend technologies, including machine learning.

Project leadership

Successfully led development of a major university research project.

Performance optimization

Enhanced application performance and reduced load times through efficient coding through debugging.

User engagement

Boosted user engagement and retention with intuitive UI designs.

Projects

ReapplyMe Sandton, South Africa 12/2024 - Present

https://reapplyme.netlify.app/

ReapplyMe is a modern Saas application designed to streamline the job application process by providing intelligent tools for managing job applications, generating personalized emails, and tracking career progress.

- Built a job application platform leveraging React, Tailwind CSS, Python and Supabase
- Implemented dynamic email templates powered by Google Gemini AI, enabling users to generate personalized emails with 95% accuracy in variable substitution
- Developed a profile management system supporting over 10+ fields for tracking skills, education, and professional milestones, enhancing user organization

Languages

English Proficient

Awards



Trontend Maestro

For Mastering the art of stunning interfaces, This award is a recognition of my ability into bringing designs into life making every project shine